hey everybody welcome to this b1 English
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as I speak you ready
so today I'm gonna talk about
universities in the US this is a subject
that I'm sure a lot of you are
interested in because maybe you've
thought about studying in the u.s. so
let's talk about some of the essentials
that you need to know about American
colleges so first things first it's
important that you know that in the u.s.
we use the word college interchangeably
with the word university you can say
either of these words and they refer to
the same thing most of the time in other
countries this is not the case I'm sure
if you go to the UK or Australia you'll
hear people use these words very
differently but since I'm an American I
tend to use the word college more
frequently than university let's talk a
little bit about the cost of going to a
four-year university in the u.s. before
we can calculate the average cost we
first need to distinguish between
in-state and out-of-state tuition what
am I talking about here well if you
attend a university that is located in
the state where you live where you went
to high school it's cheaper if you
decide to go to a university in another
state it's more expensive this is what
I'm referring to when I talk about
in-state and out-of-state tuition the
average in-state tuition for a 4-year
public university in the u.s. at this
time is a little more than $25,000 per
year I know that's a lot but it's
actually not that bad compared to
out-of-state tuition the average
out-of-state tuition for a 4-year public
university in the u.s. at this time is
about 41,000 dollars per year that's
crazy isn't it I wish I could tell you
that I were joking but sadly I'm not
this is the reality of going to college
in the u.s. so you definitely need to
think about this before you decide to
study in an American University I was
pretty lucky because my college wasn't
quite
expensive you might be wondering how
people can afford to pay these
astronomical tuition costs
the answer is student loans a student
loan is money that the government lends
to somebody to pay for college sounds
great right wrong after you graduate you
have to pay back all the money that the
government gave you plus interest
so after students graduate they spend
many years paying back their student
loans college is unbelievably expensive
in the u.s. all right let's talk about
the educational aspect of American
universities in the u.s. students can
choose their major the subject they want
to study either before or after starting
college many students don't know what
exactly they want to study so they don't
decide on a major until the end of their
second year the way this works is that
all students have general classes during
their first two years everyone takes
more or less the same types of classes
math English history science etc then
starting in their third year students
take classes specific to their major so
for example I majored in English so
during my third and fourth years of
university all my classes were related
to English but during my first and
second years I had all general classes
not all English classes this is why many
people don't decide on a major until the
end of their second year you don't
really have to decide before then I know
this is really different from a lot of
other university systems in other
countries okay lastly let's talk about
living on campus this is something that
many students do especially in their
first and second years all universities
have what we call dorms which are like
student apartments but usually very
small the dorms are located on the
college campus so it makes it really
convenient for students to walk to their
classes the downside of living in the
dorms is that you usually have to share
your small living space with other
people if you get stuck with a bad
roommate you're in for a long year I've
had some bad
roommates in the past unfortunately
another negative thing about living in
the dorms is that if you're not into
drinking and partying it can be pretty
uncomfortable for you
dorms are notorious for being places
where students drink party and get into
all kinds of trouble so you might want
to consider that before you decide to
live on campus okay that's all for today
leave a comment and tell me what your
country's universities are like I'll see
you next video
[Music]
[Applause]